[
    {
        "stepName": "Identify Motion of objects",
        "stepNumber": 1,
        "stepQuestions": []
    },
    {
        "stepName": "Write FBD equation for each Moving block",
        "stepNumber": 2,
        "stepQuestions": [
            {
                "question": "How many surfaces are in contact with the red block?",
                "options": [
                    5,
                    3,
                    1,
                    2
                ],
                "threejsstep": "fbd",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": -200,
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [],
                "type": "basic",
                "answer": 3,
                "showfc": [
                    "Upward Forces: ",
                    "Downward Forces: ",
                    "Rightward Forces: ",
                    "Leftward Forces: "
                ],
                "showfcheading": [
                    "Red block"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to c1?",
                "options": [
                    "N1 perpendicular up",
                    "N1 perpendicular down"
                ],
                "threejsstep": "fbd",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": 1,
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [],
                "type": "basic",
                "answer": 0,
                "showfc": [
                    "Upward Forces: ",
                    "Downward Forces: ",
                    "Rightward Forces: ",
                    "Leftward Forces: "
                ],
                "showfcheading": [
                    "Red block"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the direction of normal reaction on block 1 due to c2?",
                "options": [
                    "N2 rightwards",
                    "N2 leftwards"
                ],
                "threejsstep": "fbd",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": 2,
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [],
                "type": "basic",
                "answer": 1,
                "showfc": [
                    "Upward Forces: N1, ",
                    "Downward Forces: ",
                    "Rightward Forces: ",
                    "Leftward Forces: "
                ],
                "showfcheading": [
                    "Red block"
                ]
            },
            {
                "question": "At how many points does the imaginary sphere for red block cuts the strings",
                "options": [
                    0,
                    1,
                    2,
                    3
                ],
                "threejsstep": "fbd",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": -100,
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [
                    "Upward Forces: ",
                    "Downward Forces: ",
                    "Rightward Forces: ",
                    "Leftward Forces: "
                ],
                "showfcheading": [
                    "Red block"
                ],
                "answer": 0
            },
            {
                "question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the y-direction",
                "options": [
                    "+N\u2081-8=0",
                    "+N\u2081+8=0",
                    "-N\u2081+8=0",
                    "-N\u2081-8=0"
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "fbd",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": 100,
                "show1": [],
                "showfc": [
                    "Upward Forces: N1, ",
                    "Downward Forces: 8",
                    "Rightward Forces: ",
                    "Leftward Forces: N2, "
                ],
                "showfcheading": [
                    "Red block"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Red block: +N\u2081-8=0"
                ],
                "type": "basic"
            },
            {
                "question": "Whats the FBD equation of red block in the x-direction",
                "options": [
                    "+N\u2082+5=0",
                    "+N\u2082-5=0",
                    "-N\u2082+5=0",
                    "-N\u2082-5=0"
                ],
                "answer": 2,
                "threejsstep": "fbd",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": 100,
                "show1": [
                    "Red block: +N\u2081-8=0"
                ],
                "showfc": [
                    "Upward Forces: N1, ",
                    "Downward Forces: 8",
                    "Rightward Forces: ",
                    "Leftward Forces: N2, "
                ],
                "showfcheading": [
                    "Red block"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Red block: +N\u2081-8=0",
                    "Red block: -N\u2082+5=0"
                ],
                "type": "basic"
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "stepName": "Constraint Understanding",
        "stepNumber": 3,
        "stepQuestions": [
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards right with speed 5 m/s",
                "options": [
                    5,
                    -5
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 1,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    0,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string is 5 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the dog is moving towards left with speed 5 m/s",
                "options": [
                    5,
                    -5
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 2,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    0,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string is -5 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards right with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -3,
                    3
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 3,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    0
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string is -3 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string if the human is moving towards left with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -3,
                    3
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 4,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    0
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string is 3 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -5,
                    5
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 5,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    3,
                    -3
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 6,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    8,
                    -2,
                    2,
                    -8
                ],
                "answer": 2,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 7,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s",
                    "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 2m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in right direction with speed 5 m/s",
                "options": [
                    5,
                    -5
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 8,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    3,
                    -3
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 9,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards right direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    8,
                    -8,
                    -2,
                    2
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 10,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is 5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s",
                    "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is 8m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -5,
                    5
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 11,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in right direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -3,
                    3
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 12,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in right direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    8,
                    -8,
                    -2,
                    2
                ],
                "answer": 1,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 13,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    3,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is -3 m/s",
                    "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -8m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of dog in left direction with speed 5 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -5,
                    5
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 14,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "What is the rate of change of the length of string only due to motion of human in left direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    3,
                    -3
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 15,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            },
            {
                "question": "Net rate of change of length due to dog moving towards left direction with speed 5 m/s  and human moving in left direction with speed 3 m/s",
                "options": [
                    -2,
                    2,
                    -8,
                    8
                ],
                "answer": 0,
                "threejsstep": "constraint Understanding",
                "threejssubstep": 16,
                "threejssubsubstep": [
                    -3,
                    -5
                ],
                "show1": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s"
                ],
                "show2": [
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of dog is -5 m/s",
                    "Rate of change of length of the string due tp motion of huamn is 3 m/s",
                    "Total Rate of change of length of the string due motion of both human and dog is -2m/s"
                ],
                "type": "basic",
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": []
            }
        ]
    },
    {
        "stepName": "Constraint Equations",
        "stepNumber": 4,
        "stepQuestions": []
    },
    {
        "stepName": "Final Answers",
        "stepNumber": 5,
        "stepQuestions": [
            {
                "question": "What are the final accelerations, tensions and normal reactions?",
                "options": [
                    "N\u2081= -8.0, N\u2082= -5.0",
                    "N\u2081= -5.0, N\u2082= -8.0",
                    "N\u2081= 8.0, N\u2082= 5.0",
                    "N\u2081= -5.0, N\u2082= -8.0"
                ],
                "answer": 2,
                "threejsstep": "motion",
                "threejssubstep": 0,
                "threejssubsubstep": 0,
                "show1": [
                    "Red block: +N\u2081-8=0",
                    "Red block: -N\u2082+5=0"
                ],
                "showfc": [],
                "showfcheading": [],
                "tobeshown": 1,
                "show2": [
                    "Red block: +N\u2081-8=0",
                    "Red block: -N\u2082+5=0",
                    "Final Answers: N\u2081= 8.0, N\u2082= 5.0"
                ]
            }
        ]
    }
]